alumniclass.com 2016-08-11

# Privacy Policy :: AlumniClass.com

## Privacy Policy

Last updated January 22, 2013. 

**•COLLECTION AND USE OF INFORMATION  
• EMAIL COMMUNICATIONS  
• SITE COMMUNICATIONS  
• REGISTERING WITH OTHER SITES  
• YOUR PUBLISHED INFORMATION  
• WHEN YOU VIEW MEMBER PROFILES  
• SITE USE  
• INTERNATIONAL USERS  
• CHILDREN USING THE SITE  
• SECURITY OF YOUR INFORMATION  
• CHANGES TO OUR PRIVACY POLICY **

This Privacy Policy applies to any information Alumniclass.com receives, collects and stores through our Websites and is incorporated into all other domains or Websites owned and operated by Alumniclass.com. Other domains or Websites owned by Alumniclass.com currently include: [www.classyears.com](http://www.classyears.com/), [www.reunionposts.org](http://www.reunionposts.org/), [www.highschoolalumnireunion.com](http://www.highschoolalumnireunion.com/), [www.reunionguidebook.com](http://www.reunionguidebook.com/), [www.johnnyandran.com](http://www.johnnyandran.com/), [www.pawzoom.com.](http://www.pawzoom.com/). We intend to create more Websites. 

Each Alumniclass.com Website may offer different features, functions, services and tools. We share the information you provide between our Websites when you register or upload any content. This privacy policy is Alumniclass.com's company-wide Privacy Policy with regard to any information and data we collect. 

**COLLECTION AND USE OF INFORMATION**

Alumniclass.com does not share your information with third-party solicitors unless you are a reunion coordinator or committee member seeking reunion planning information from outside sources. If you have a dispute regarding a reunion or purchase of reunion tickets your email address may be shared with the reunion coordinator in order to assist you with your dispute. Reunion related disputes are the responsibility of the reunion coordinator and by registering for a reunion or purchasing reunion related items you agree your email address may be shared with the reunion coordinator. 

Alumniclass.com retains the right to use your information (e.g. your name, where you graduated from, your class year and any other information deemed necessary by Alumniclass.com) in promoting our Websites to other alumni, website members, users, schools or school districts, through communications such as electronic newsletters, emails, and other lawful means. 

When you co-register with other websites, information may be shared between Alumniclass.com and the websites with whom you co-register. This may include pre-populating our Websites with your information through the co-registration process. Examples of co-registering may include, but are not limited to, **Facebook** , **Twitter** , and **Pinterest**. As with other social networking sites, the information you provide when you register and create your profile (e.g. your name, e-mail address, hobbies, occupation, marital status, work place, community affiliations, and similar information) on any of our Websites shall be maintained by Alumniclass.com and some or all of your information may be displayed on all Alumniclass.com Websites. Information we display on our Websites will not include your email address. Although e-mail addresses are often required, you may not be required to verify your email address to become a member. If you provide an invalid email address, you will not receive email notifications. 

Members are given the option to submit more detailed information about themselves, including their maiden name, city in which they reside, birthday, marital status, and activities in which they participate. Because this information is publicly displayed on our Websites, it may appear in the results of searches conducted through Internet search engines while you are a member of our Websites and potentially for some time after your membership is terminated, depending upon the search engine's indexing practices. Because this information is public, it may be included on third-party websites and devices and your geographic location may also be displayed based upon the Zip Code you provide, mapping, community affiliations, to assist members and visitors to the websites with a tool to help find people. 

The Alumniclass.com Websites where your information may be shared and publicly displayed include, but are not limited to, [www.classyears.com](http://www.classyears.com/), [www.reunionposts.org](http://www.reunionposts.org/), [www.highschoolalumnireunion.com](http://www.highschoolalumnireunion.com/), [www.reunionguidebook.com](http://www.reunionguidebook.com/), [www.johnnyandran.com](http://www.johnnyandran.com/), [www.pawzoom.com.](http://www.pawzoom.com/). 

**EMAIL COMMUNICATIONS**

By registering on any Alumniclass.com Website and providing your email address, you agree to receive email communications from us and agree that we can and will email promotions, newsletters, apparel sales, discounts, updates, reunion information membership, paid promotions, information about and from all Alumniclass.com Websites and any other information that Alumniclass.com determines to be necessary to you as long as such information is lawful. If you wish not to receive certain emails from Alumniclass.com, you can change your email settings or Unsubscribe from certain or all emails. You can change your email settings by logging-in and then going to "My Profile" and "Update Settings". From there, you can make changes to your email preferences. If you need assistance, please email Customer Support. You may be required to follow the Unsubscribe option provided in email communications from us, depending on which of our Websites you have unsubscribed. Please note that when changing your email preferences, you may still be emailed administrative notices or other necessary information regarding your membership, profile or account. We reserve the right to send you email communications related to your membership and other transactional emails without offering you the opportunity to opt-out because such are required to maintain your account. 

**SITE COMMUNICATIONS**

When you register as a member, you will receive emails from us alerting you about other member activity, uploaded content, photos, your membership, your profile, when others view your profile, or other similar messages and communications. We may also email other messages, communications, alerts, membership notices and other informational emails to provide instructions on how to use your membership, promotions or other services. When you register you will be automatically enrolled in one or more of our regularly recurring emails, such as our newsletter, site usage alerts and other marketing promotions. All these communications include all Alumniclass.com websites and may also be sent to your inbox on any or all of our websites. 

Each commercial email communication from us contains instructions on how you can remove yourself from our mailing list or how to opt out of certain emails. Please keep in mind that any changes that you make to your email preferences may take up to seven (7) business days to process. Each commercial email may have its own separate opt out process and each site owned and operated by Alumniclass.com may have their own opt out processes. If you have questions or trouble opting out or changing your email preferences, please email our Customer Support. 

When you or any member sends emails through the website's internal email system, the website is designed to hide email addresses to protect the privacy of both the sender and the receiver. When sending or posting messages or email communications on the site, it is up to you to choose to disclose your email address to the receiver or any other personal contact information you choose to share with others. We respect your privacy and the privacy of all members and only read or disclose email communications when we believe it is necessary in order to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, improper site conduct, suspected fraud, threats to the physical safety of any person, violent behavior, violations of this Privacy Policy and/or our Terms of Service, or as otherwise permitted or required under state, local or federal law. Please keep in mind that you will not be able to delete, revise or otherwise recover any message that you send once you have sent your message or email. Please remember, you or the member receiving a message or an email must be a paid member in order to read or respond to received message and/or emails. 

**REGISTERING WITH OTHER SITES**

We may provide the ability to register with select third-party sites such as Facebook, Twitter, Pintrest or other third-party sites. In some instances, we provide co-registration to help access your information from other third-party sites and to pre-populate registration fields and other information about you. If you co-register with third-party sites and accept their terms of service, then you are automatically registered as a member of their websites and your personally identifiable information is shared between our site and any third-party site with whom you co-register. As a result, you may receive information from these third-party sites. We are not responsible for the use of your personally identifiable information by any third-party sites. In order to cancel your membership with other sites, you will need to do so from the other site. 

If you join any of our Websites using Facebook Connect, Facebook Open Graph, Facebook API or any other similar provider that utilizes your information and provides it to us, we will receive information, such as your name, email address and other information that may pre-populate our registration form within your profile. Using such services allows you the option to post information about your activities to your profile page and this information may be shared on the Website in the same manner as all other information you provide us during the registration process. 

You may also visit third-party websites such as Facebook, Twitter, Pintrest and similar sites not operated by Alumniclass.com that are connected to our Websites for our users benefit and access. Such sites are operated by external, third-party service providers. These third-party sites have their own separate terms of service and privacy policies. Alumniclass.com is not responsible for your use of sites not owned or operated by Alumniclass.com. Other sites may set their own cookies, collect data, or solicit personal information. It is your responsibility to check the Privacy Policy and Terms of Service of any site before offering any of your personal information. 

**YOUR PUBLISHED INFORMATION**

Information that you submit to message boards, live chat functions, photo albums or similar places on our Websites may be displayed to other registered members and to the public, so please exercise caution in what information and images you disclose. Alumniclass.com may, at our sole discretion, remove certain content or information posted on our Websites but assumes no responsibility for doing so. We may also show your membership status on the Website to inform others of your membership type and the membership options available. 

We will not share your published information with third-party sites, unless you have co-registered with that third-party site. Exceptions include the necessity to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving emergencies, potential threats to the physical safety of any person, violations of Alumniclass.com Terms of Use, or as otherwise required necessary by site administration, regulation, court order, governmental requests, law enforcement, or to prevent, investigate, identify persons or other entities potentially involved in suspected illegal activities or anything that may expose us to legal liability. 

**WHEN YOU VIEW MEMBER PROFILES**

You may find and view other members and their profiles on the website. When you view other profiles by browsing the website, clicking on a profile, viewing a profile, clicking on photos or a photo in a yearbook page, using people search tool or otherwise any activity that may take you to a member's profile your profile viewing is tracked by the website and in some cases shared with other members. Each time you visit another member's profile, your name and the date of your visit will be viewable by that member but only upgraded members are able to see who has viewed their profile. You may remove that specific visit to another member's profile page by clicking on the remove visit button when you view a profile. You may also choose to opt out of having your name automatically left on other members' profiles when you view their profiles. Which you can do by accessing "My Profile" when you are logged into the website and then select "Profile Views - Opt Out". 

**SITE USE**

A. General Data 

We store the information that you provide to us and the information we receive through your browser on our servers and server log files. This information may include Internet protocol addresses ("IP Address"), the type of browser you use, your Internet service provider ("ISP"), and other data we receive by any lawful means. We may use such information to track and analyze your internet use, user data and to detect fraud or other types of potential abuses, and to gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. 

B. Cookies and Web Beacons 

In the internet context, a "cookie" is a piece of information or file that a website may upload to a user's computer for record keeping and tracking purposes. We link cookies to your account and use them to personalize your experience on our Websites. This may include, but is not limited to, remembering your preferences, your profile information, and customizing any content provided to you. Cookies help to measure the aggregate or total usage and traffic to our site. We also use cookies to track what website pages you visit. You may configure your browser to reject cookies, but this may interfere with some of the features of our sites. 

A web beacon is a tiny graphic with a unique identifier that is placed on a web page or in an email. Its function is similar to that of a cookie and is used to collect specific information, such as the time and date of your visit to our Websites, and a description of the page or as a cookie identifier. We tie the information collected by web beacons to your personally identifiable account information and track your account preferences. We also may use web beacons to compile aggregate data about our user's website browsing habits and in email messages sent to you to track email data and how you respond to email content and promotions. This allows us to study the effectiveness of certain emails and the effectiveness of marketing campaigns. 

C. Log Files 

We automatically gather certain information and store it in log files or on our servers. This information includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring or exit pages, your operating system, date and time stamps, and the areas "clicked" on our Websites. We use this information to study user trends, track users' movements on our Websites, and to collect other demographic information about our users. This automatically collected data is NOT linked to any personally identifiable information. 

D. Publicly Displayed Content 

Any information you submit on any message board, blog, and public forum or anywhere on our Websites can be viewed by anyone and becomes public information. Such information could be used by other users. We cannot be and are not responsible for that personal information which you choose to submit. Use caution when you choose to submit information, comments or any other content anywhere on the sites. We reserve the right to remove any submitted content at any time, but do not assume any responsibility for the removal of same. 

E. Personal Profile Information 

When you choose to register our Websites, you create a profile identifiable to your account. When you create a profile, you can share as much or as little information about yourself as you wish. The profile information you provide is publicly viewable and may be included anywhere on or throughout our Websites and on third-party web sites if you have co-registered with a third-party site. Use care in providing personal information that you may not want publicly disclosed. 

F. Member Activity 

Any use you make of our Websites, for example viewing other member profiles, posting messages, making comments, sharing information, uploading photos and so forth, is known by us and may be displayed, shared with other users, or used to market promotions related to the site. If you do not want this kind of information displayed, you should not join or use our Websites. 

G. Membership Cancellation 

You may, at any time cancel, your membership and remove your profile from the site by logging into the site, clicking "My profile", followed by clicking "Account", and then using the membership cancellation option on that page. If you have questions or trouble cancelling your membership, please email our Customer Support for assistance. All fees relating to any paid membership and any subsequent automatic renewal fees are non-refundable. 

**INTERNATIONAL USERS**

The information we collect and maintain is located in the United States. Our privacy laws may not be as protective as those in your country of origin or geographic location. If you are using our Website from any area, location or country outside of the United States, by providing your information to us you are consenting to the transfer of your information to the United States for processing and maintaining in a manner consistent with our Privacy Policy. 

**CHILDREN USING THE SITE**

We do not knowingly collect any personally identifiable information relating or pertaining to a child. For purposes of this section, a child is any person under the age of 13. In the event that we learn that a child has submitted, we have collected, or a child's personally identifiable information has been posted to any of our Websites, without prior parental consent, we will take steps to delete such information. 

**SECURITY OF YOUR INFORMATION**

We have installed physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards to store and maintain your profile and member information in a reasonably secure environment. You will be required to use a password to access certain areas of our Websites where certain types of your information can be changed or deleted. It is of the utmost importance that you take precautions to protect yourself against unauthorized access to your password. More specifically, it is your responsibility to maintain the confidentiality of your password. It is your responsibility to be aware of the information you place on your profile that you deem private. We cannot guarantee that the safeguards we employ will maintain the privacy of profile information from the threats of others and factors beyond our control 

**CHANGES TO OUR PRIVACY POLICY**

Alumniclass.com may update this policy at any time as our collection of information or other privacy practices or policies change. When we make any material changes to this privacy policy we will post changes to this page and changes will become effective immediately and the date of any such changes will be displayed as last updated and the corresponding date. You should review this page from time to time to review changes to our Privacy Policy. 

Thank you!
